Śrīla Gurudev was never a poser.
Śrīla Gurudev non si è mai atteggiato.
These self-promoting “advanced gurus” from Vr …
Questi sedicenti "guru avanzati" da....
they are relishing mellows … It’s all bullshit.
stanno assaporando la dolcezza... sono solo stupidaggini.
[The Real Vaishnava]
[Il Vero Vaishnava]
Alright? Clear and simple.
Giusto? Chiaro e semplice.
Gurudev didn’t play those games.
Gurudeva non faceva quei giochini.
He told someone once, when they asked him
Una volta disse a qualcuno, quando gli fu chiesto
about some spiritual practice, he goes,
di alcune pratiche spirituali, disse:
“Do you want me to make a show?
«Volete che vi faccia uno spettacolino?
Should I make a show for you?
Dovrei mettere su uno spettacolino per voi?
And then you’ll feel like you’ve got a guru?”
E poi vi sentirete come se aveste un guru?»
So, we know. the real Vaishnavas, like Puṇḍarīk Vidyānidhi,
Allora, come sappiamo, i veri Vaishnava, come Puṇḍarīk Vidyānidhi,
they are keeping what they’ve got suppressed.
trattengono ciò che hanno soppresso.
Svarūp Dāmodar—suppressed.
Svarūp Dāmodar, soppresso.
That’s why Śrīvās Ṭhākur teases him,
Per questo Śrīvās Ṭhākur lo prende in giro,
and Mahāprabhu [goes], “Oh-oh! Don’t tease Svarūp Dāmodar.”
e Mahāprabhu: «Oh oh! Non prendere in giro Svarūp Dāmodar».
Then it all comes out.
Poi viene tutto fuori.
So, Gurudev, he is keeping it suppressed, within him.
Allora, Gurudeva, lo trattiene dentro di sé:
“I am just a simple village boy,
«Sono solo sun semplice ragazzo di villaggio,
I was naughty boy before, now I am good boy.”
ero un discolo prima. ora sono un bravo ragazzo».
And all these kind of things.
E tutte queste tipo di cose.
He is actually telling you the truth.
Vi sta in realtà dicendo la verità.
They think, “Oh, he is playing or he is being …”
Alcuni pensano: «Oh, sta scherzando oppure sta...».
He is actually cleverly telling you what the truth is.
Vi sta in realtà con abilità dicendo qual è la verità.
We were in Geneva with Gurudev,
Eravamo a Ginevra con Gurudeva,
and we go to the Vedanta society, or the Ramakrishna Mission, whatever.
e andammo alla Vedanta Society, o Ramakrishna Mission.
And there is this Indian there, and he is going like,
E lì c'è questo indiano, e dice:
“I am the only Swami in all of Switzerland,
«Sono l'unico swami dell'intera Svizzera,
and I have a PhD in bullshit.”
ed ho un dottorato in stupidaggini».
Then Gurudev goes, “Oh, very …”, you know.
Allora Gurudeva: «Oh, molto...», avete presente.
So he invites Gurudev for this …
Allora invita Gurudeva a questo...
it was Ekadashi, I remember, as I recall, anyway.
era ekadashi, ricordo, comunque.
So we are having this program.
Allora, c'è questo programma,
And what he does, where you should be introducing Gurudev,
e quello che lui fa, quando dovrebbe presentare Gurudeva,
he is telling everyone how qualified he is.
dice a tutti quanto lui sia qualificato.
“And I got my matriculation from […],
«E mi sono iscritto a...
and I got an MA from here, and I got a PhD from here,
ed ho conseguito un master qui, un dottorato lì,
and I did this, and did that, and I am the only person,
ho fatto questo e quello, e sono l'unico,
and I am this, and I am that …”
e sono questo, e sono quello...».
And then he does this whole thing.
E poi dice questa cosa:
“And now I introduce this Swami … Err … What is? … Govinda.
«Ed ora vi presento questo swami... uhm... cosa è?... Govinda.
From, you know, the Bengal.”
viene, sapete, dal Bengala».
And then Gurudev, like you know, with his cane, he goes,
Allora Gurudeva, con il suo bastone, dice:
“I am not so qualified.
«Non sono così tanto qualificato.
Actually I am just a village boy
In realtà, sono solo un ragazzo
from a little village in Bengal.
da un piccolo villaggio nel Bengala.
I was not … I have no higher education
Non ero... non ho un'istruzione alta,
I only went to …”
sono andato soltanto alle...».
Maybe fifth grade or something; he didn’t even go to high school.
Forse alle scuole elementari o qualcosa del genere, non è andato neanche alle scuole superiori.
So Gurudev starts telling how unqualified he is.
Allora Gurudeva cominciò a dire quanto fosse poco qualificato.
“And Prabhu here, Swamiji, is extremely qualified in so many ways,
«Ed il prabhu qui, swamiji, è estremamente qualificato in molti campi,
I could never hope to be [as] qualified as he is, I am just a simple village boy,
non potrei mai sperare di essere qualificato quanto lui, sono solo un semplice ragazzo di villaggio,
so you’ll forgive me for not being so qualified.”
dunque mi perdonerete per non essere altrettanto qualificato».
And then he said,
E poi disse:
“But my Guru Mahārāj is very qualified.”
«Ma il mio Guru Mahārāj era molto qualificato».
This is Gurudev. He goes,
Questo è Gurudeva. Egli disse:
“My Guru Mahārāj is very qualified,
«il mio Guru Mahārāj è molto qualificato,
and by his grace he took pity on this unqualified person
e per la sua grazia, ebbe pietà di questa persona poco qualificata
and extended something to me.”
e mi ha insegnato qualcosa».
Then he quoted a śloka.
Poi citò uno śloka.
Maybe about the gratitude of disciple for guru,
Forse sulla gratitudine del discepolo per il guru,
how rare it is to find guru in the world,
di quanto sia raro trovare il guru nel mondo,
even more rare to find a qualified disciple.
persino più raro è trovare un discepolo qualificato.
Then he talked a little bit more about his disqualifications
Poi parlò ancora un po' della sua incompetenza
and quoted another śloka, another śloka …
e citò un altro śloka, e poi un altro śloka...
Long story short, with each śloka that Gurudev quoted,
Per farla breve, ad ogni śloka citato da Gurudeva,
and it’s a heavy Sanskrit, not the simple stuff that everyone …
ed è un sanscrito difficile, non le solite cose che tutti...
Not, you know, yadā yadā hi dharmasya …
Non, avete presente, yadā yadā hi dharmasya…
I mean, that’s beautiful, but …
Ossia, è bellissimo, ma...
I mean to say like heavy, esoteric, long Sanskrit.
Voglio dire, un sanscrito difficile, esoterico, lungo.
Every time Gurudev …
Ogni volta Gurudeva...
Because the man sat like this, like a cock [sits up straight].
Perchè quell'uomo si sedeva così, come un gallo.
As Saraswatī Ṭhākur said;
Come diveva Saraswatī Ṭhākur,
he was talking about “the leg of a cock”.
parlava della "zampa di un gallo".
That’s what the materialist is.
Questo è ciò che un materialista è.
They are so proud, their stride …
Sono così orgogliosi, la loro camminata...
And he says, “All you do is “Go!” [gesturing to send away]
E dice: «Tutto quello che fai è [gesto]
and knock them over.” Done.
per farli cadere». Fatto.
But they are strutting around like proud cocks.
Ma se ne vanno in giro come galli orgogliosi.
Gurudev … One śloka— the man’s head goes [lower].
Gurudeva... Uno śloka, e la testa di quella persona [si abbassa]».
Two ślokas—[even lower].
Due śloka, si abbassa ancora di più.
Three, four … twenty ślokas …
Tre, quattro... venti śloka.
After around thirty ślokas he is like [bents down very low].
Dopo circa trenta śloka
And Gurudev, he is going, “I am not so qualified.”
E Gurudeva, diceva: «Non sono qualificato».
“I am not so qualified.
«Non sono molto qualificato.
And then he quotes another śloka,
E poi cita un altro śloka,
and then in the end the guy is like … [bent down]
e alla fine il tizio sta tipo... [piegato in avanti].
In the name of praising that man you annihilated him
Con la scusa di lodare quell'uomo, lo hai annichilito
and showed the world what a pompous ass he is.”
ed hai mostrato al mondo che pallone gonfiato sia».
That’s His Divine Grace Śrīla Bhakti Sundar Govinda Dev-Goswāmī Mahārāj.
Questo è Sua Divina Grazia Śrīla Bhakti Sundar Govinda Dev-Goswāmī Mahārāj.
Hare Kṛṣṇa!
Hare Krishna!